Hi everyone, thank you for coming to my
talk. Uh so my name is Jenny Guanichu
and I'm a AI security researcher and my
research is currently backed by this uh
venture capital called Pebble Ventures.
Uh brief uh background, I am a CTF
player. Our team won third place in
Defcon last year. uh and I uh uh before
last year I wanted to do uh a uh to
build a math AGI but then I realized
that like I can use the skills I had at
Caltech for building math AGI to for
cyber security which is a field I'm
extremely passionate about. So um here
it's uh so I choose uh Linux kernel for
um my research because uh kernel patches
still get lost in 2025 and there's like
1,400 emails per day on Linux kernel
mailing list and volunteer uh mainers
get drowned. There's no centralized
tracking. Uh so basically there's a huge
infra issue for uh Linux kernels and
kernel testing is uniquely hard because
you need uh real hardware across
architectures uh and you know there's a
lot of um CI but there's no CI
coordination. So that uh more CI does
not mean better uh CI. And what I found
in uh Lind's kernel is that there's
125,000 labeled vulnerability data set
which is the data set is what's
important for building machine learning
models and uh basically uh there's this
uh fixes invention where you have
different commits and some commits
introduce vulnerability. So a later come
would refer to the previous commit with
a fixes tag like in this case the fixes
uh to refer to that uh commit that
introduced vulnerability and this is
great because like label data set uh I
can use it to train my machine learning
model and uh when I look into the Linux
kernel bug uh distribution uh it's
actually interesting because 13% of the
bugs hide for uh over five years and uh
there are different kernel sub system
have different bug lifetimes. Um so uh
canvas and uh like this there's also
this 19 years bug that was hidden in the
Linux kernel which is super interesting.
Um it was introduced in August 2006 and
fixed in August 2025. And what's really
interesting about this is that uh this
uh commit itself was a fixing commit. Uh
so
uh when I analyze all the bugs, it
appears that bugs introduced in recent
years uh get fixed much faster. However,
that's actually not entirely true
because the data is right censored. Uh
what we found uh the bugs that were
introduced in 2022 uh are uh like found
like much faster because we just haven't
it's only 2026 right now. We just
haven't had the time uh to have really
long living bugs and um you know race
condition bugs hide the uh longest uh
because you know we need to trigger them
spec uh like very specific conditions uh
and it's just not very easy to find um
and there's also a lot of uh incomplete
fixes um so uh I want to talk so there's
this anatomy of long lived bugs for
example uh there's a reference counting
errors uh they don't crash immediately.
They leak memory slowly. Uh so you might
not notice until months later and then
there's missing null checks after
dreference. Uh the compiler might
optimize away uh the no check since you
already dreferenced uh and they survive
because the pointers really know in
practice. And there's also integer
overflow in size calculations and uh
race stations uh race conditions in
state machines uh which require precise
timing to hit. Um and there's the 20 bug
fixers. I'm going to shout out to them
in the Linux kernel. And
uh uh who fixes these bugs most often?
uh which was also really interesting
when I looked into it uh in the top 10
super reviewers and uh Dan Carpenter
beyond his like uh 2,000 bug faces also
invented the fixes tag convention uh so
I wanted to train my model and before I
trained any neural model I I was like
what if I just uh do do a very dumb uh
dumb thing where uh for example uh the
the B1 it's just three numbers like
lines added removed file changes changed
on all the uh diffs and this was
surprisingly it was able to get uh area
under curve 0.779
and uh a little background what is uh
the area under curve what curve curve uh
so the curve it's actually modeling uh
the recalls and um basically uh 0.779
means that for every uh thing uh like
the reason that it's so good is because
there's just so many uh there's not that
any vulnerable uh commits. So that if
you just guess like safe for all of
them, you're going to get a pretty good
like accuracy. Uh so uh and B4 it's just
the commit subjects only. And uh B6 is
combined on subjects and the diffs. And
uh basically what this tells me is that
if your model uh cannot beat these like
simple dumb baselines and it's just a to
a fancy tokenizer um because this is
there's no like neuronet networks in
here. they're just you know um do domain
knowology decision trees for uh B8 where
uh it's uh I trained it um uh 118
handgineer features uh looking at the
diffs uh and telling me uh if the diffs
actually uh have like uh the for for the
um features that the div has uh training
on them and uh uh another thing I
realized is that the token sizes matter
because uh different models have
different token sizes basically how much
is it able to look at at the same time
and at 15 512 tokens uh transformers
they read messages not code meaning uh
meaning like they don't get to see all
of the uh diffs uh and so I was able to
increase it to 8 8,000 tokens and it
achieved a much better result so context
length unlocks code understanding uh and
another thing is vulnerability patterns
have a shelf life so uh the models I've
trained uh I looked at how how good it's
able to predict uh over uh like
different time periods for example um
like and I I realized like it's able to
uh do much better in the earlier ones
than later uh so uh this tells us like
how often we need to like update the
models when we uh train them and another
uh thing I under realized was that
curriculum learning was backwards
because when I first started training
that I thought that large complex diffs
with u many pattern uh imbalances are
very hard to classify. Uh however, the
reality is that large diffs are there's
more signals. It's easier. Uh it's u so
uh but but the small diffs with like not
that many context changes are are a lot
harder for the models because there's
less signals. And so the actually a hard
example samples are like one to five
line changes with simple uh missing note
checks or uh you know refcon increment
without obvious error path and lock
requiring one function releasing
another. And another thing I I found out
that's really surprising is that uh
instead of having better architectures
what actually really helped was having
much better data sets. So uh uh after
doing some research like the authors uh
I listed here uh I found out that hard
negatives aren't universally good. So I
in the beginning I curated my data set
with a lot of uh very hard um negatives
meaning that uh like uh the positive
classes uh uh like so like it's for me
those are very hard uh bugs to find uh
and however actually uh what really
helped was to include a lot of uh easy
uh bugs for the model because like the
model needs to learn what is obvious is
safe before learning what is subtly
dangerous because like most bugs are
obviously safe and um uh
yes and that is um that is my um my
progress learning and understanding and
uh I have a blog post here uh linked at
the pebble website and my Twitter it's
Guanichu uh so the blog post actually uh
went to number one on hacking news and
there's a lot more details on the blog
post and uh yes um and I'm open to Any
questions?
>> All right.
I love the cheats idea. I think it's
like like a fuzzing sort of approach.
Was there some cheat that you uh thought
would fool the model, but it didn't?
Like you're like, "Oh, this is a great
cheat. This isn't going to trick it."
But then it didn't trick it.
>> Um,
so, uh, what do you mean by cheats? Uh,
like
>> it was on your slide. You said like
there were these cheats where you tried
to kind of fool the model by just
putting three numbers and seeing if it
would get confus easily confused by you
injecting three bogus numbers. There was
like a slide you had that um had two or
three. Yes, this one. The four examples.
Was there any of these um
uh
maybe cheats? I thought I thought I
thought I read or heard the word cheats,
but was there anything any of these
examples uh that you thought would kind
of fool and get a higher score, but
actually the model was good enough to
reject your attempt to fuzz it? Does
that make sense?
>> Actually, that's like uh that's a great
question. And what happened was actually
the opposite of it. I thought that these
are not gonna work because these are
just so silly you know like uh instead
of looking at the code diffs like the
actual diffs uh that introduced the
vulnerability which is where the
vulnerability happens. You just look at
the numbers like how many lines were
added in this commit uh how many were
removed and what are the file names that
were changed and I was like this is not
very relevant to like the vulnerability.
So like I was like uh the model is not
going to do very well with only these
three numbers and what's surprising is
like the model is actually doing pretty
well and the reason is that there's just
not that many vulnerability uh
vulnerable commits. So just by like um
so just by like even the model if the
model doesn't learn uh very well just by
blendly you know guessing and matching
on these superficial patterns it's doing
pretty good on the recall like uh like
giving it a 100 uh 100 uh vulnerable
commits or like safe commits how many of
it uh how much of it is it able to guess
correctly and since the ratio I just uh
saw like one-sided where the majority of
the commits are um are safe, the model
can just do really well. So this is
what's really surprising to me. Uh
>> it's surprising to me too. That's why
it's a great uh I think this is the
slide of the talk for me. So really
great job.
>> Yes. So like yesterday I remember like
uh Kini like Nicholas Kini was talking
about how he was able to use cloud code
to find like hundreds of crutches in
this kernel. uh and uh I I it's
extremely interesting but because like
uh this is the issue that um I'm also
like facing is like there's a lot of
false positives uh in the model the
model can like tell you oh this looks
suspicious I have this level of
confidence that this uh commit is
vulnerable however uh there's no way to
verify and even if like there's crashes
crashes does not mean actual
vulnerability uh it does not mean you
can actually exploit this bug uh so
there is there's a long like a big gap
between uh crashes to actual like
exploitations. Uh so yeah uh so but I
think this model this like this
experiment is super interesting because
like imagine uh we can use this on the
hundreds of crashes that um Nicholas
Cornini has and then like point uh point
him and his spring power onto the ones
that actually are a lot more suspicious
like higher severity in his rating uh as
to like uh so he prioritize his time.
Yeah. Any more questions
>> or thoughts?
>> That's it. Well, thank you very much.