All right, thanks very much. Uh, so I'm
Brendan Dolan Gavit. I used to be a
professor at NYU. Now I have jump
shipped to industry where I am an AI
researcher at Expo. I also want to
introduce my co-presenter, Vincent
Olsen. I want you all to write down his
name because a few years from now,
you're going to want to be able to say I
saw one of his early talks. Brilliant
guy, very happy to be working with him.
So today we're going to be talking about
one of the what I think are the harder
current challenges in automated web
security which is finding authorization
and authentication bugs right and these
are classically very very difficult
because as some of the earlier talks
we've seen have already mentioned it's
all about verification
right and so this is going to be largely
about how do we find and verify
vulnerabilities in authentication and
authorization.
>> Yeah, we so we were a bit unsure what to
call this talk. One of them was like n
minus one factor authentication or my
favorite one which was no of [laughter]
but yeah the you know the moral of the
story is that authentication is actually
very hard right and why is it hard well
there's so much of it we have http basic
o we've got ooth 2.0
signed URLs, JWTs,
OIDC, OOTH 1.0, Keraros,
magic links, session cookies, TOTP,
LDAP.
But what I think is probably one of the
most common O mechanisms in the world is
custom off, [laughter]
right? Where the developer just said,
"Yeah, I'm pretty sure I know how to do
this." wrote their own O system, set up
all their own authentication,
authorization checks, and shipped it.
Okay? And so with all of these different
types and complexities, you don't really
have any hope of writing a classical
validator that just says, "Yes, I can
tell you exactly when this
authentication fails." And so that's
where we start to turn to AI.
>> Yes. What really matters is that the
client and backend can work together.
And even if people implement OOTH 2,
it's not necessarily spec compliant.
So the way we do authentication at expo
is that we start with an agent with a
browser give it credentials ask it to
log in uh and then just like with
exploits right we might have false
positives so we validate we have the
validator for checking whether it's
actually logged in and then we also want
to be sure that it understands and that
has reverse engineered enough of the of
the application to actually like take
the browser state and turn it into API
uh requests to also have a a validator
for that. So if an agent passes these
two checkpoints, we're pretty damn sure
it's logged in.
Now
it can be a bit hard or these validators
took a lot of effort to get right. So I
think let's play little game which is
like is this locked in? Yeah. Do you
want to raise your hand? Do you think
you're logged into Apple here?
Got some yeses. Some people many shy
people. [laughter]
So in this case I thought I was logged
in but I wasn't. And another case we
have here right is if we look at this
this uh request right here just from
this request I wouldn't be able to
determine whether the request is
successfully authenticated. It could be
a public phone book right and then uh
then the off material likely doesn't
matter. could also be a a medical
appointment booger and then this was
likely be a a a real authenticated
request. I think the the trick we found
is finding places in the app where
there's a contrast between being locked
in and locked out. But with this
validators,
how can we use it for evil? [laughter]
Right? So we have our agent.
If it passes the two checkpoints, we're
damn sure that it's locked in. What we
could do is instead of giving the
username and password,
we could just remove the password. If it
locks in, then bam, we have an
authentication bypass.
So, here's a very cute bug found by
Horizon 3, which is very easily
demoable. So, what happened there was
that the default secret key was
hardcoded in the code.
So our agent there looks through the
source code, finds a way to forge um new
session tokens using a secret key, the
hardcoded secret key, loads the state
into the browser, boom, admin access.
And now our validators are happy.
We can also find MFA bypasses because to
log in on sites that requires uh second
or multiple factors, right? We need to
give them access to those factors. So
what we could do is simply just remove
it. If the agent logs in the validators
check, boom, MFA bypass.
Okay. But you know, one thing I I always
think about is like, okay, but it's
actually somewhat rare to screw up so
badly that you get a complete
authentication bypass, right? Much more
common is you have working
authentication,
but now you've messed up something about
how people authorize get authorized to
access particular resources. So, this is
where I feel like we go from evil to
diabolical. That's our goal in life is
to be as evil and diabolical as possible
for good.
So, okay, let's consider this scenario.
We've got one authenticated session as
admin
browsing around the site. It makes a
request to some endpoint with its admin
bearer token.
Now to understand whether that endpoint
requires some kind of authorization, we
would like to be able to make the exact
same request but under the context of a
low privilege user, right? But
unfortunately there's no guarantee that
we can get something like that, right?
Because if you just browse around as a
lowprivilege user, maybe you never even
see the admin interface in the first
place. And so what we want is some sort
of magical transformation
between
the request as made from an admin
context to a request as made from a
lowprivilege context. Okay. And so we
use the highly technical term off
transmogriation here. And it turns out
that this is actually a script that you
can get an agent to write for you,
right? Its inputs are a browser state
and a URL. and its output is a request
as made correctly under that
off context.
[clears throat]
Right? And so now we can make that
request and if we get a different answer
as the low privilege user as the same
answer as uh from the low privilege user
and the admin then that means that the
endpoint is potentially public, right?
It may also mean that you've completely
forgotten to do any authorization
checks. So you have something like an
IDOR, right? And we're actually going to
not focus on idors for the rest of this
talk. We're going to consider them out
of scope. Um because that actually
requires some judgment, right? That's a
judgment call as to whether the response
should be considered public or not.
Okay? So we're going to focus on
instead, right? So if we get this back,
we're going to say okay, let's not be
further interested in this for
authorization bypass purposes
and instead let's look at the case where
you get a differential response. Okay,
so you access it as admin, you get back
a user profile, you access it as a low
privilege user and you get back a
forbidden. Okay, so the application is
trying to do some kind of authorization
check here. That does not mean they did
it correctly, right?
So let's assume that we have we're in
this case where we get different
responses.
Now we have a very concrete goal that we
can send an agent after and we have a
very concrete way to verify when that
agent solves the task when that agent
finds a bypass. Okay. So what does that
goal look like given this endpoint and a
lowprivilege context?
M find me what the response would be
from the highprivilege admin context.
Right? And this is great because now we
can give this as an answer key to our
validator. Right? The validator is going
to get to see what the response looked
like under the admin session. The attack
agent only gets to see what the URL is
and has to produce the admin's response.
Okay. Now, if it manages to do so,
great. Now, we have a validated
authentic uh authorization bypass.
Otherwise, we can reject it. And this is
great because as capable as these AI
models are, when you give them a task
like find a security vulnerability, no
matter what, they're going to end up
making things up.
Okay. So the other nice thing about
this, I've been talking about
authorization uh bypasses, but if you
want to get very technical, we can also
use this to find authentication bypasses
at the API level by just saying, okay,
one context is low privilege, one
context is completely unauthenticated.
Okay. And so this is quite nice. So
there's actually a fairly wide variety
of different things that you can detect
with this, right? because this covers
things like uh JWT forging attacks, all
the clever crypto cryptographic tricks
where you can take a token, change the
claim somehow, resign it. Uh you can
find classic these broken object level
authorization checks, session expiration
kinds of things, hard-coded tokens, and
these fun little ones like parameter
bypasses where you try to access uh a
URL, you get rejected, but then you add
admin equals 1 and suddenly you're
accepted. Okay, so again in the spirit
of show rather than tell, uh so last
year we put in a bunch of manual work to
set up an instance of the Redmine
project tracker and try to find uh
authorization issues in it by planting
CTF style flags in it and then using
that as our verification. Um it turns
out that uh if you're trying to deal
with something like uh thousands of bug
bounty targets or the entire open source
ecosystem, you cannot go through set all
of those up by hand and plant uh CTF
flags in them. So we wanted to be able
to see if we could reproduce this kind
of vulnerability in a more automated
way. Okay. And so the nice thing about
this, so now we have this script that
can make requests from different
authorization contexts.
And so we can get this kind of nice
prioritize list where we say great here
are the endpoints that you want to look
at that give different responses when
you're authenticated versus
authenticated unauthenticated versus
authenticated as a low privileged user
or when you're authenticated as a low
privileged user versus a higher
privileged user. Okay. And so in this
case it uh the one that we're going to
look at is this project's endpoint down
there where when we visit it with a low
privilege user we see one public
project. When we visit it with a higher
privilege user we see one public project
and one private project. Okay. And that
gives us the differential we need to say
this is a target for an attack from the
low privilege to high privilege.
So let's look at this trace. So this is
where it started out. The other nice
thing is that once you produce this
script, it's a really powerful tool for
the agent to use. It doesn't have to
reverse engineer the authentication and
authorization mechanisms every time,
right? You just give it a Python script
and it can use it. Now it starts off by
getting a baseline request. It
discovers, okay, great. I see that I can
only see this one project.
We move on. It starts looking through
source code. And by just the fifth
iteration, it's actually already found
the parameter that's going to allow it
to bypass things. So it turns out that
when you set admin projects equals 1,
you bypass the visibility checks, right?
And so it starts running the code,
starts confirming it. It can use again
this uh same authentify
transmogriification script um to get a
differential between what it looks like
uh with admin project equals equals 1
and without that it discovers that hey
oh there turns out there's a secret
project right and so it sees that
there's another project that it's now
able to see it submit that to the
validator
and now the validator luckily has a very
very easy job. It can just look at what
was submitted, right? Okay, the agent
submitted something that lets me see
both projects. When I look at this with
a high privilege user, my ground truth,
it was also able to see both projects.
That means the agent has successfully
bypassed the authorization check. Okay,
so this is quite nice, right? This lets
us go um very quickly
[clears throat] to the vulnerability.
And we found that also when we're giving
it these very very targeted tasks, we
don't need very very longunning agents
to find these vulnerabilities usually.
Right? So success.
Um, [clears throat] one thing I'll say
uh that's not in the slides is we also
have a much more fun vulnerability uh
involving a case where by translating a
URL from English into French, literally
changing one of the words into French um
you can bypass authorizations in a CRM
and access any document. So uh if you
would like to hear about that one, it's
not fixed yet. So, we're operating under
what I call the bureau day vulnerability
program where you buy us a beer and
we'll tell you about it. [laughter]
Okay. So, uh this does have limitations,
right? I called out one of them. These
classical idors aren't something that
we're trying to detect with this
approach because classical doors don't
show this differential between different
off contexts. Right? I go to uh you know
shopping cart five. I go to shopping CL
cart seven as different users I can see
the same thing does that mean that I
found an idor maybe maybe not you have
to exercise judgment about the
application there we're looking for
these more technical authorization
bypasses
the other thing is that this is heavily
dependent on the quality of that off
transmog modification script that the
agent wrote right and so we really have
to be very careful to make sure that it
doesn't make very many mistakes when
writing that script. But one thing
that's kind of cool is we get tons and
tons of built-in test cases for whether
that script is working by letting agents
just explore the site with a browser,
letting the JavaScript code make
requests and recording the responses and
then that gives us a test suite that we
can use to validate this um off
transformation script. All right, so
thanks very much for listening. Um we
had a lot of fun with it and we'd be
happy to answer any questions.
>> [applause]
>> Who's got questions?
There's always questions.
Uh, I guess we really focused on like
one specific validator. Can you kind of
give us a sense of like how you came up
with this idea and other types of
validators that you you sort of build?
>> I think for this one we already had the
login validators, right? So that it
really was like how could we misuse it
by using all components we we had
already and then I think Brenda and I
met a met at a hackathon and then we
implemented it and it worked and we
found some bugs.
>> Yeah. And I think that I mean the other
thing is that um it really did come out
of trying to just make the product more
reliable because getting logged in and
staying logged in is super hard but also
super important for doing a good pen
test in the first place. And so as we
like got these uh validators of are you
logged in, are you still logged in and
really banged on them in some of the
craziest sites you've ever seen, aka
internal um banking apps, uh [laughter]
you end up uh finding a lot of the
corner cases, ironing them out, and
ending up with these really robust
validators. And we wanted to then also
reuse that work to be able to find cool
new vulnerabilities, too.
>> What else? Greg, we got one up here.
up here.
>> Mice's coming.
>> Thank you. Um, hey guys. I, by the way,
OOTH 2.1 does force the spec. So, two
fixes the 2.0. Just just try to do it
right. Um, I like So, this was this was
great. Thank you so much.
Are you proposing this as a way to
enforce proper authentication for AI
agents? this just hey use this in
agentic workflows or is this like what
how can we use this in the world within
agentic because I'm I'm big on assigning
identity and and tightly bound scopes so
you can reduce the blast radius and the
damage is is that the problem this is
solving
>> so this is more aimed at saying I have a
web app that uses authentication and
authorization like many do I want to
bang away at this app and find the
vulnerabilities in it before they
shipped, right? So, this is more about
[clears throat]
uh the offensive security side, trying
to find vulnerabilities in web apps as
opposed to securing the agents
themselves.