Um, all right. So, hi everyone. Thank
you so much for having me. My name is
Olivia Galuchcci and I work at Data Dog.
And today I want to show you an AI
workflow for Mac OS vulnerability
research. So, before I begin, I want to
mention a tool I published called OSS
Sensor. OSS sensor generates a
prioritized evidenceback research queue
derived from Apple OSS diffs, basic
binary features, and log templates. It
applies custom rule-based scoring to and
uh supports rule-based triage and the
binary and log analysis components are
intentionally lightweight and there is
no integrated LLM vulnerability
verification. It's designed as a tri and
hypothesis generation aid not as an
automated vulnerability discovery tool.
And there's two versions of this
project. One without built-in AI and
then one with AI capabilities. The nonAI
version is more streamlined and
significantly easier to adapt if you
plan to integrate your own AI workflow.
I strongly recommend this approach
because it's what I do uh particularly
if you intend to iterate quickly or vibe
code your enhancements. And this way it
will be personalized to your setup and
won't be dependent on how I set it up.
That said, the PR for plug-and-play with
AI API keys is still under review. And
that is because parts of my workflow
which this talk and tool is inspired by
includes intentional manual intervention
steps. While I was developing this
process, I quickly learned that certain
configurations become extremely costly
depending on usage. Thus, I'm unsure who
might really want a plug-and-play
version, especially if you're a beginner
in the VR space on Apple operating
systems. And if you'd like to explore
this tool, there's several built-in
demos available. When connected to an AI
coding agent, the tool will outline the
required execution steps and demonstrate
scoring and weighing out of the box. And
from there, you can incorporate your own
AI workflow. Given the tool's simplicity
and its modular design, this should be
achievable within a few simple prompts.
And this talk will cover where AI has
helped me in my research process and how
I've influenced AI to better suit my
needs given that around a year ago, many
AI chatbots could not tell you how to
access logs on Mac OS.
So in this talk, the AI vulnerability
research components we will focus on are
reverse engineering and fuzzing. Reverse
engineering is inferring how a compiled
system works from binaries and runtime
behavior, while fuzzing is automatically
generating and mutating inputs to
exercise system and surface bugs via
crashes or violated invariants. My
workflow tries to automate steps in
these areas that I've found to be most
reliable. First, the AI workflow treats
AI's o or sorry, treats Apple's open
source code as a sensor. And a sensor is
any data source that produces signals
about a system or state change without
doing interpretation for you. Second,
the workflow then uses AI agents to turn
that sensor into our prioritized queue.
So, what changed, what looks security
relevant, what to reverse, and what to
fuzz. And for context, an agent is a
system that can take goals, select
tools, run steps, and produce structured
outputs. The problem is that Apple ships
a huge security surface area, but only
some of it is open- source. Like Apple
has over 400 public repos, but these
releases are incomplete and very hard to
keep up with manually. So my time is
limited by bandwidth. Thus, the story
I'm going to tell is diff to hypothesis
to harness. And the trick is that we
will augment open- source diffs with two
other signals, binaries and OS logs. Now
before I really get into things I want
to address the elephant in the room
which is Apple's secrecy. Apple actually
open sources a lot more than people
expect. So the X and U kernel core
libraries like lib system lib lib
dispatch um and some historically like
damonss like launchd but they don't
publish everything. Some components are
missing or only partially available
including things like core foundation
and CF network iOS specific drivers and
core crypto which comes with additional
redistribution constraints. These source
drops can be incomplete or outdated.
You'll see headers referencing files
that don't exist, which can be very
confusing for an AI agent or
instructions that are missing. Um, and
for context on these constraints and why
this workflow matters operationally, I
recommend watching my Bsides 312 talk,
which covers the history and manual
version of the process I'm about to
discuss. So, what does this have to do
with AI? Well, the information overload
with Apple's 400 plus open source repos
is exactly why AI agents help in this
context. If I rely on a human, aka
myself, to do manual repo exploration
and one-off diffs, I end up with a
narrow view of risk. If I automate that
bookkeeping, I can spend more time on
the parts that AI isn't working well for
me yet, which is reasoning about
privilege boundaries and exploitability.
I've even found this helpful for threat
detection engineering. This matters
because the faster I can understand what
changed, the faster I can build
detections and prioritize around new
attack mechanics. So even though the
code is incomplete, it can still guide
my research. The key is for both me and
AI to treat it like a map. You might not
have that full territory, but these
landmarks are real. And what I do and
what many researchers do is to use
Apple's open source as a reference while
working with the proprietary binaries.
You'll take a binary like launchd,
sislog d or a driver, and you'll use
whatever logs or sources exist to match
known functions, annotate call patterns,
and reverse unknown logic. The agent
angle is simple. This hybrid method is
effective but doesn't scale. Agents can
do the repetitive steps. So, correlate
symbols, chase string anchors, retrieve
relevant source context, and produce
structured summaries that make a human
reviewer faster and more consistent.
Even when symbols are uh stripped,
structure plus string constants plus sys
call usage lets you map back to open
source code. And four common tools show
up constantly. So, like strings gives
you debug messages, format strings and
file paths. what can extract version and
project info. Uh then there's nm which
will list s symbol names if they exist
especially in unscripted binaries or
frameworks. And then class dump is great
for interface information especially
like private frameworks and objective C
method surfaces. And when I'm trying to
map binaries back to source projects I
also use Apple's distribution manifests
to cross reference components per
release. I look at the release metadata
when it exists. And I look for version
strings or source file names via strings
or what. All of these repetitive but
context dependent steps are the exact
operations I hand to agents as tools. I
don't want the model inventing facts. I
want to call it calling strings, parsing
the output, retrieving the corresponding
source chunks, and then producing a
bounded conclusion with citations to
what it observed. After this, I usually
want to go deeper with binary dipping,
which is comparing binaries before and
after a patch to identify changes. Here
is my like all-time favorite example.
So, in 2016, OSX Reverser used diaper to
diff syslogd from version 101.2 to
101.3.
He found that only one function had
changed and that change was an
allocation math fix. Value + 4 became
value x 4 + 4. And from an exploitation
mindset, that's suspicious because it
looks like a heap overflow mitigation.
And there was a string nearby that
stated add lockdown session reallock
failed. And that was a [clears throat]
hint back to the source. This kind of
surgical dipping is how vulnerabilities
get reversed after a patch. And it
matters because these fixes often need
to be applied in multiple locations. If
identical code is patched in some files
but not in others, the unpatched ones
can remain vulnerable. and the larger
and more bureaucratic an organization
is, you better bet that there's going to
be repeat mistakes in the neighboring
files of their products. Now, imagine
that exact workflow only with AI running
continuously on every Apple release. It
would ingest new OS OSS tags and
tarballs and distribution manifests and
compute diffs at function and semantic
level. Then it would score changes for
security relevance based on patterns
like allocation math, bound checks,
entitlement gating, XPC parsing, and
IOKit external method table changes. It
would correlate the binaries and string
anchors, then emit a ranked Q with why
this looks risky, plus pointers for a
human to validate. For my solo offensive
research, this was a throughput
multiplier. I've only tested this on
small individual components, never the
full OS because again, cost constraints.
But it would be awesome if I could
expand it to something like that. And
for an organization, it would compress
the loop from Apple shipped something to
we've identified the shifted behaviors
and services so we can adjust our focus
monitoring and our triage faster. I'd
imagine if this was scaled, it would be
the kind of workflow you'd expect from a
dedicated vulnerability research team
that tracks platform changes as a
routine operation rather than a random
lady building nonsense with her
computer. And that's precisely why I
think this is worth discussing openly.
It helps keep vulnerability discover
discoverability accessible to the junior
engineer which is me. Now here's the
architecture I've had the best results
with. First I use an agent pipeline
approach. uh this means that I am
utilizing a coordinated set of tool
using agents that turns raw inputs in
this case diffs, binaries and logs into
evidence-backed outputs like uh ranked
triage cues, hypothesis and buzz/
telemetry plans that I start by using a
retriever. This is the indexing layer
that searches embedded information like
oss code, symbols, notes, and log
templates to return the most relevant
context for a given question or
artifact. And then I use a toolbox was
like which is like a a curated set of
deterministic analyzers and system
commands like strings o tool class dump
and log queries the agent calls to
gather facts and generate evidence
instead of guessing then more agents
handle it. I use different agents for
diff triage re context hypothesizing
planning and analysis. I'm unable to
tell you which like specific AI models
and agents aren't most effective because
I kind of had the ones that just like I
I just stuck with like I started using
and stuck with them. But I'll explain
more on how I account for that later. I
don't treat the model as god. I treat it
as a junior junior engineer that can
read uh fast follow procedures and
generate structured hypotheses that we
can validate with reversing tracing and
fuzzing. Additionally, it's important to
remember that each step in itself can
break and that they're all depending on
each other. Thus, your setup should
ideally account for that since you might
be on a paid personal plan with limited
resources.
The big addition to this talk versus
like the classic I used Apple OSS to
reverse stuff is logs. Unified logging
gives you subsystem and category labels
that map back to components, stable
message releases and strings that can uh
help you hunt in binaries and source as
well as execution hints that you can use
to reconstruct data flow diagrams
without the full source. I treat unified
logs as a pivot into attack surface and
code paths, not as like a doctrine
because of how noisy and bulky these
logs are and I don't always know how to
handle that. They're good at telling you
which components actually handled the
output uh or input. So like uh things
like subsystem or category plus sender
image info and then what error paths
fired that can reveal like parsing
assumptions, type expectations, and uh
IPC contracts. And that's pretty good
ROI for target selection, hardness
design, and what to fuzz next. An AI
agent in general can do like three
useful bounded tasks with logs. First,
it can take a long a log line and find
where that string lives in a binary via
strings and then locate its basic block
and callers. Next, it can retrieve
adjacent OSS code for those callers if
it exists and produce a structured
summary like inputs, trust boundaries,
and parsing. Lastly, it can feed that
summary into fuzz planning in or like
into detection engineering like what to
watch, what parame what parameters are
attacker controlled and then what
failure modes might look like. And this
is relevant to developing PC's as well
as like localized endpoint tests or
detections. So when your privileged AI
pipeline learns a new untrusted input
boundary or a new privileged XPC entry
point, you can translate it into to
telemetry requirements and correlation
rules. And in general, that's how you
turn vulnerability research into
coverage. Only in the past, we did it
manually. The same idea applies to those
like back in the day uh kernel
extensions. By diffing kx across
versions, researchers have found changes
to external method tables that surface
new or patched entry points in IOKit
drivers. And uh what this uh fuzz
planner agent produces, it's not an
exploit unless like you made it do that
somehow. It's a plan. First, it
enumerates candidate services like SIS
call handlers, IOKit, user clients, XPC
uh services and parsers that you focus
on the entry points where attacker
controlled inputs actually cross trust
boundaries. Then it produces a minimal
test harness uh like a test driver
including the invocation path, the
entitlement requirements and the
expected input shape so that the target
is actually reachable and reproducible
at scale. Next, the AI recommends a seed
strategy by extracting dictionaries from
strings, mining parameters from logs, or
bootstrapping from observed traffic so
that the coverage ramps quickly instead
of mutating from nothing. Note that if
the command is not available in the
subset that I provided, you can add them
yourself or connect an AI uh search
chatbot so that it can find them
automatically. I don't ne necessarily
recommend just like allowing your laptop
to just like run whatever you want and
Google whatever you want and just like
go ham. Um but if you have test MacBooks
and all that stuff, go ahead and do that
because it can be cool. Um also like the
seed strategy part is the method for
selecting and generating the initial set
of representative inputs that bootstraps
a buzzer's coverage and guides the
mutations towards a highv value code
path. Finally, the AI defined success
metrics like crash bucketing, sanitizer
signals, and unique stack traces so that
you can identify progress and you know
ideally turn these results into
actionable research.
Where this AI workflow breaks down today
is when you ask for full chain exploits.
To be honest, I'm not at the point in my
research career where I am finding full
privilege escalations and like disabling
all the Mac OS security controls.
Additionally, I've spent significant
time just trying to understand and test
how the operating system is working. And
this knowledge is great for that
learning by doing approach too. That
said, these models will occasionally
invent steps, especially if you hook up
an AI uh chatbot. And so I try to keep
it as constrained as possible due to the
nature of how large these subsystems are
and how much information I am sending
and how much money it takes to process
all of that information. So the
constraints I put on it is like bug
class prediction and harness design.
Those are the highv value outputs and
then humans own the exploitability. This
also keeps the larger AI models which is
primarily what I use uh happy given that
a lot of them try to put mechanisms to
lock them down for offensive research
purposes. And if you're like me and
don't fully trust your first past
instincts, it helps to sanity check like
your ideas on what to exploit against
high quality public works. For example,
Patrick Wortle has an extensive body of
writing and I use AI tooling to check
whether or not my hypotheses line up
with established techniques in his
published analysis as well as my own
notes. This isn't wired into the OSS
project yet, but I might add it since I
do these sanity checks quite frequently.
Also, credit where it's due. I
intentionally licensed OSS sensor as
GPLV3 because I learned a lot from GPLB3
licensed work by Patrick and many others
and keeping that code sharable helps
others build and learn in the same way.
So the TLDDR is that even partial source
is powerful. Combine it with binary
analysis and you can reverse Apple
subsystems with surprising accuracy but
there are constraints which is that you
know incomplete OSS releases, obuscation
and licensing. You need a pipeline that
is compliant by design with like the
local indexing, careful handling of
source drops and providence tracking so
that you can explain every conclusion.
All of that said what did we learn? The
core idea I want to leave you with is
that Apple's partial open source can be
treated as a sensor stream. It's not the
full system, but it's a steady source of
change signals, and those signals become
much more valuable when you can process
them continuously. The workflow I showed
takes that sensor and turns it into a
prioritized research queue using AI
agents, but with a very specific
philosophy. The model is not God. It's a
tool using Juno annualist.
uh this the work uh happens in
deterministic tooling and the model's
job is to stitch together the evidence,
retrieve the right context and produce a
structured outputs that make a human
faster and more consistent. That's why
the narrative is diff to hypothesis to
harness. You start with a diff source or
binary. You ask what meaningfully
changed and where the trust boundaries
might be. Then you turn that into a
testable hypothesis about a bug class.
It can help with size calculation
issues, parsing assumptions, policy
gating, and interface surface shift.
Then you build a minimal test driver so
that the path is reachable and
reproducible, which sets you up for
fuzzing and for validation. The trick is
that the open source diff alone is not
enough. We need to augment it with two
other signals. the binaries because they
reflect the reality of what ships and
then the OS logs because unified logging
is a good ROI pivot point and to which
components actually handled that input
and which error paths fired. The fuzz
planner piece is an example of how this
stays like practical and bounded. It
doesn't generate an exploit. It
generates a plan and it tells you which
surfaces matter, how to quickly reach
them with a minimal harness, how to seat
inputs so that coverage ramps quickly
and then how to measure the results so
that you can identify findings. And
importantly, it acknowledges the limits.
Open source releases are incomplete,
binaries can be opaque, and models can
hallucinate. And that's why everything
is evidencebacked, providence tracked
and compliant by design.
So I personally stopped throughout this
process. I've utilized tools like uh
like AI tools like chat GBT's deep
research but given the cost constraints
manual review is required for me
especially if it looks like something I
won't understand given these systems are
great but hallucinate and given that I
might not always know what I'm talking
about it's imperative for my research to
have these manual checks finally uh this
isn't just like a offensive research
like productivity hack the same pipeline
shortens the loop for localized threat
detection engineering when you can
quickly identify what changed and what
behaviors and interfaces moved. You can
update monitoring, prioritization and
triage faster and turn that platform
churn into detection coverage. So these
are the outcomes I care about which is
you know making Mac OS vulnerability
research more scalable, more teachable
and more operationally useful. Um I have
more in terms of where we can go from
here. Uh I released a uh Apple security
focused newsletter called Retreat to
Read after I graduated. Um where I post
approximately once a month uh or once
every other month and uh yeah so thank
you so much for providing me the
opportunity to present. Um hope you all
enjoyed. Let me know if you have
questions.
All right. While uh while the shy people
in the audience start to raise their
hand, I'll start with one. Um, you kind
of talk a lot about it being a a junior
analyst because of sort of cost and
manual review trust. What would have to
change for you to to uh to start to give
it bigger tasks to have it take on more.
It's just reflecting on sort of Dan's
talk as
>> it's constantly getting better.
>> So, I am very lucky that I have a ton of
test machines. I have a ton of tests,
tons of iPads. Like I have a test m for
like everything, right? So, I'm able to
outsource certain things that maybe the
average person wouldn't be able to do.
But when I think about it, this is like
tens of thousands of dollars of research
devices. And I'm like, is is like the
[laughter] a like I'm talking about
accessibility, but it's like, is the
average person going to be able to get,
you know, researchers and things to like
send them these devices? Are they going
to be able to afford this? And when I
tried to scale it down so that like I
could do research like on the go and
things like that, I was like, I can't do
this. like like what is going on? And I
when I started like looking at like the
tokens, the cost constraints, like dude,
you hit a grand quickly when you're
putting in entire subsystems of
operating systems. So I would say just
give me lots of money.
[laughter]
Does anyone want to follow that? Yeah,
that's the problem. Uh uh awesome. Well,
thank you so much