Do I do I actually get more time? Uh,
>> all right.
>> I don't know. People are going to be
upset if I start three minutes earlier.
They're scrolling in.
>> No, start. All right,
>> everyone.
So, my name is Rob Lee, one of the uh
18,000 Rob Lees that running around in
cyber security at this point. I'm going
to get the uh volume of this thing down
whether it's going to kill me or not.
So,
three years ago, maybe two years ago, I
started, you know, being asked a lot of
questions about AI. And I have to admit,
I don't know that much about AI. I'm
still learning. I'm uh like many of you,
struggling on a daily basis. And I think
it's important to call out the fact that
not everyone rolling around here is in
fact an expert. I basically dabble a
heck of a lot at this point. I am
learning on a daily basis. And I find
when you end up starting to really focus
in on this stuff, the more you feel
overwhelmed, the more you feel like
you're sinking on a daily basis. So,
having developed the SIFT workstation
starting in 2008, so this is almost an
18-year project at this point of a
massive amount of digital forensic
sensor response tools that initially
started as an education capability that
most started using on their backend on
being able to do digital forensics into
response on a daily basis inside their
own organizations. So the premise of
this talk is what if you take an
extremely vetted beat to shreds tool and
you combine it with a little bit of AI
reasoning and let's see what happens.
This is entirely an experiment I decided
to do based off of and again you'll
laugh at this. Sans Marketing came to me
and said, "Get, hey, Rob, we need you to
do something digital forensics, which
you're known for, and combine AI into
it, and we have you scheduled for a talk
in November 15th, and this date is going
to come key here in a second, November
15th on a Sunday to discuss your
findings." I'm like, "Cool." So, about 6
weeks prior to that, it occurred to me
because I'm playing around with cloud
code a lot. What if I installed cloud
code on the SIFT workstation and see
what it can do? So, that was the premise
of the talk. I did some experimentation
and my mind was blown. So let's talk
about this. Um sadly not really sadly
two days before my discussion in the
talk I was giving anthropic released
their report using cloud code on
offensive operations and I was a little
bit bummed about this because apparently
the Chinese had the same idea I did
which is combining cloud code with a
bunch of operational tools and to let it
go. And that's essentially what we are
doing here with cloud code. Now what we
ended up finding here is that when you
accelerate offensive operations
using automated AI reasoning, you're
able to achieve a speed that goes from
that goes from things that used to take
days if not weeks to seconds and
minutes. And again, if you've started
playing around with this or started
taking a look at the speed of what is
documented by anthropic on the what they
observed, it is mind-numbing. So, in
order for us to be able to figure this
out on the defensive side, we need to
say, hey, you know, the idea is matching
AI speed with AI speed. So moving to the
next slide when you end up taking a look
at what we are supposed to need to
accomplish being able to do manual
hands-on typing to do digital forensics
instant response work to discover what
is in AMC cache let's do prefetch
analysis let's do event log analysis
let's combine that into a timeline using
plaza let's do memory analysis all of
these things combined take a lot of time
so kind of curious poll for the audience
In order for you to analyze completely a
single system during incident response
from start to initial touching of the
system whether it's a deployed agent
you're imaging a post image by the way
you have the C drive image how long does
it take you from start to finish to
create a report final report time frames
throw out numbers
>> what's that
>> three days
>> two to three days.
>> What's that?
>> Awake sometimes.
>> Maybe a week sometimes.
Any other anyone could do it faster? A
day. I chose a day because otherwise the
numbers just look unbelievable. What if
I said you could do a full day of manual
forensics to report in 14 minutes?
Okay, we'll come back to this. All
right.
>> Breaks the business model. and going to
everyone's going to be a little bit
scared what I'm about to show you but at
the same time you're going to like wait
that's a gamecher
and only someone who knows digital
forensics into response can comprehend
the report so I don't want to say this
is the end of human existence when it
comes to digital forensics there's no
way if you look at the output I've put a
bunch of resources in the slack if you
look at the report if you just say
figure that out it is not you need to
have a formal understanding of what this
looks like so when you take anthropic
code, the reasoning side, you add an MCP
and you add it to the SIFT workstation,
the peanut butter and the chocolate.
Here we're sitting on top of something
that does natural language processing
basically in your uh clawed prompt. You
basically ask it a question and that
question could be do memory analysis. So
here's essentially what you would do.
You would ask a question. You have the
memory image there. I'd like you to
analyze this memory image and find
anything malicious.
It automatically knows based off of the
context that you provided just and I
redid this yesterday just as a test a
little bit of training giving it
contextual analysis of the different
tools that are on the SIFT workstation
telling it how it works maybe even just
using public guides. I even had it go
look at the man pages, run the commands,
pull out the flags, understand what the
command line interface is, and then it
built the cloud MD file and the
skills.md files that are sitting
underneath each of the different tasks
that you wanted to accomplish. So to
give you an idea of what this looks
like, I like demos. Essentially, I have
multiple images in here. Um, and I
basically say, oh, that's the wrong one.
You ask it to basically find evil in the
memory image. It goes through
and you can see here, but pay close
attention to the minutes it takes for
the overall processing. And again, I
might just go and skip to the end here.
It's because it's more fun to be able to
see what the output is.
Again, 18 minutes to do this image. And
what we end up having here is a final
report for the memory forensics. And
this automatically creates this by the
way because you asked it to. You end up
seeing in here the adversary achieved
initial execution using WI.
And you can see me scroll through the
overall report here. Finds a malicious
binary p.exe into masquering temp
directory. You get a system profile. All
this stuff is automatically determined
for you. Threat actor context attack
chain
malware deployment persistence. It's
kind of going fast here because I have
limited amount of time. code injection
analysis, network connections, command
and control, full malicious process
tree, chronological activity. I didn't
even tell it to do this. It just did it
because I gave it context surrounding
the tools, what this looks like. It
probably went online saying here's what
an official report looks like and false
positives. It found f response for the
imaging capability for the agent. It
recommends remediation tactics and then
it has the output reports that it has
created here. All that took a single
memory image about 18 minutes. The only
reason it took that long is because I
had to press yes on continue continue.
Now I've gotten around that. But from
initial build yesterday just to test the
theory one more time. An hour and a half
of skill building and I gave it a memory
image and then I hit go. Now the
resources I'm distributing at the end of
the week or end of today, sorry, end of
week. I'm like thinking teaching here
again. At the end of the day, I'm going
to give you access to all the memory
images and C drive images. So, you want
to replicate this, by all means, do it.
Now, you need to test this stuff too.
So, the brain behind this all is a cloud
MD file. It basically is the prime
directive, the orchestrator that's
sitting behind the scenes. It is
allowing you to do deterministic
boundaries. You could hard code the tool
path. You don't need to let it guess. It
is allowing you to say run this
capability. Do not run this one. I also
could give it some rules like I had to
figure this one out too. Questions asked
during a test. Run end to end. Don't ask
for directions. Just move through the
overall aspect of what I'm trying to get
it to do. Then we need to build its
skills with so many capabilities built
in the sift workstation. We need to have
some familiarization here that is going
to hopefully reduce the overall context
rot be able to give it a path to
success. And I'm not even building full
skill-based MCB servers. I'm just
basically giving it MD uh markdown files
for what the skills are. Here's your
goals. Here's what they do. Here's how
you potentially execute this. So if I
say I'd like you to do memory analysis
is automatically to be able to go do
this. Now again as a part of this you
know resources I have all the skill
files all the cloud MD files the overall
one and the subdirectory one all created
you could go back and replicate this I
have instructions I have a notebook LM
you could ask it I would like to go
through and do this it is all sitting
there in front of you uh feel free go
about your business so what about errors
this is where you could ask it and build
into the contextual analysis and have
something continually running behind the
scenes that says if you receive an error
I would like you to start performing
selfcorrection. This also helps with the
overall context rot that is achieved.
Essentially if you continue running the
case again and again and again it'll
slowly over time forget the context
earlier in the case. The other thing
that's really fascinating here about
this is that once you go through a
single image in a single case, it'll
remember aspects of that initial
intrusion, especially if you're hitting
other systems. So if you find a
malicious code on one system, it's
assuming it's looking for something
contextual related on system 2, system
3, system 4. So the speed naturally
increases as you're working through the
different exercise. So because people
don't like me talking about things, let
me just show how this works. So demo
time number one. Here's the threat
group. Here's what happened. We end up
having Stark Research Labs. For anyone
who's taken 508 at SANS, you'll
definitively remember this network. We
have a catalyst. Lead researcher Tim
Dunan inadvertently signaled project
completion on Twitter. What a dork. What
is he thinking here? Our carbon lab just
consumed 9 gawatt of energy and could
likely power a small city overnight.
What was I thinking? Uh going to be
fired. Uh, the breach adversary Crimson
Osprey leveraging historical tactics of
AP Hydra and AP Hammer. Yes, they're
totally fake by the way. Uh, impact
critical infrastructure exchange mail
server and web server forced offline.
Compromise vectors perimeter defenses
bypassed. Key administrative accounts
compromised deep system persistent
established local defense status. You're
overwhelmed because you're using
hands-on keyboard. So what you need to
achieve scope of the compromise the hunt
for persistence to track lateral
movement and assess exfiltration.
So once I have all this built you have
all of your disk images memory images in
here the single command that I type
find evil
in
and I type this one out because it's fun
to just watch. Look how slow humans are.
Type type type. And this is the only
command that I gave it for writing that
comprehensive report. Write compre
comprehensive report. And then of course
I had to think about well what does that
mean? And I'm like comprehensive
report in PD. I'm like my brain's on
melt here. Backspace backspace back
in PDF. Good English there Rob. All
right.
And we go.
And when you end up watching this, you
can see it's actually executing a lot of
cool things. I'll just let this run for
a little bit so you could see what this
looks like behind the scenes. Now, this
is on 16x. Of course, if you're watching
the minutes, you know, scroll by, you
could tell that is not reality.
It's finding things, finding things,
finding things.
In total at the end here
we are at 14 minutes 27 seconds for the
analysis of that C drive. Pretty cool.
Let's take a look just to reemphasize
the length of time that this took.
This is the report that it automatically
generated without any additional input.
You can see the executive summary.
And by the way, in terms of accuracy,
since I compromised the system, I
definitely know everything that's on
here. This is 100% accurate for what
it's finding here. It creates a
timeline, initial access, and again, I'm
releasing this report so you could go
through it and examine on yourself.
Malware inventory
persistent mechanisms
PowerShell transcript evidence
>> did not miss anything
network indicators a compromise
actually by the way kind of skipped by
it is the MITER attack um
overlays on top of this too and then
went through remediation recommendations
and steps um when you end up taking a
look this report offline, you're going
to notice that this is earthshattering
fun. What the heck? An hour and a half
configuration. There's got to be a
catch. As far as I can tell right now,
the catch is
AI weaknesses, context rot,
self-correction. It works out of the box
just like everything else in AI. But the
more you repeat it and repeat it, repeat
it, repeat it, over time it is going to
slowly
become more dumb just because of the
fact how that you know functionality
works. The more you're running it
against the same type of intrusion uh
that you're taking a look at. So and
again when we end up taking a look at
this I have some additional stuff at the
end here I'm going to cover. We need to
increase the speed of our instant
response capabilities to match the speed
of the offensive teams leveraging the
same capabilities.
This is amazing. Great proof of concept
here. But one more thing I'm going to
cover. One more thing. So in order for
us and I'm going to be talking about
this at the RSA talk as well that I'm
going to be giving in about two weeks.
When we are starting to think about
leveraging what we have as a community
over what the adversaries and the threat
groups and the criminal organizations
don't have is we have a lot of us and
they have a small development team and
they usually work in secret. They
usually don't like to share their toys
with one another. On the o uh opposite
side we have the open source community.
All of the things I'm showing you here,
the SIFT workstation, all the tools, all
the capabilities is open source. Now, if
you noticed a small little project that
started on a weekend in someone's
basement in November,
by the way, I kind of use this as a
justation, but Claudebot
was created over a weekend at the end of
November. It really became popular at
the beginning of January in which the
news started to really accelerate on it
and logarithmically accelerated from
that point. Part of the reason is you
have a lot of eyeballs hitting it, a lot
of developers simultaneously hitting
that one point in time and it explodes
into a significant revolutionary AI
capability.
despite your skill level, despite if
you're an AI developer, if you're really
good at forensics, if this is your first
foray into AI, what if we bring the army
of cyber defenders together and saying,
"Let's start working on this as a
whole." Now the other thing I noticed
over the past couple years and I become
fascinated with it is that these
concepts that the AI community is doing
called hackathons.
Hackathons are designed to take an
initial proof of concept and accelerate
it into a worthy true candidate capable
of being deployed at enterprise
environments that will reduce the
overall capabilities or reduce the
overall mistakes and increase the trust
of these capabilities inside the
organizations. So what the outfits and
teams don't have is a thousand of us and
what if SANS because we're giving this
away for free anyways we sponsor a
hackathon trying to get the entire cyber
security community working on this
together. So the idea here is we have
two tracks that we're going to have a
bunch of cool prizes for. I'll give you
a hint at one. We're for first prize,
$10,000
for the team or individual that has the
most significant development and $7,500
for the second team. Those two tracks
we're going to be looking at is number
one is a forensic MCP engineering. We
have a bunch of tools. Claude doesn't
know how the parameters, outputs, and
failure modes natively. I'd like you to
take my proof of concept and accelerate
it to 10 to 100x. So by the end of the
hackathon starting 1 April through May
15th we're going to be able to develop
as a community something that you'll be
able to have trust capability and
potentially counter the offensive teams
that are starting to leverage cloud
code. Track two is to cure the context
rot issue. How would we potentially go
about doing that? In the end what I'm
hoping for is having a total of $22,000
a total prize pool. I've reached out to
Enthropic because I'm very interested in
seeing if they're going to be able to
give tokens uh you know so you don't
have to spend a lot of cost developing
this behind the scenes so that they'll
be able to work with us and be able to
give resources to the community. I'm
going to have disk images. I'm going to
have memory images. I have the sift
workstation. I have an example exemplar
uh uh case that someone's turned in.
Steve Anson from SANS has developed his
own backend. So you could look at that
and saying that would be a pretty good
implementation. You could build off of
that. But the idea here is we want to
work together as a community because
there's a there there I'm looking at and
the question is can we create a very
solid instant response AI capability by
one June. That's my challenge to the
community and I think we could do it. Um
this is my contact information. The
resources have been posted in the Slack
channels and more of those resources.
I'm putting up a website. I was hoping
to get it done tonight, but just like
everything else, I can now say, "Hey, I
get get something done in a day." And
that day is going to be protocols.
It's going to have all the resources,
all the images, this presentation, a
description, what it is, everything
else. I'm going to build this probably
up in about a day or two. Just
registered the domain yesterday. Contact
information, everything else, resources
online, and questions.
>> That was fantastic. Okay, questions.
Um first okay
>> uh hi I was uh curious about the context
rot problem and how you sort of
navigated it. You mentioned that you
didn't give uh cloud code like all of
the sift manuals at once. How did you go
about like the I guess like the lazy
loading of it like was there an
orchestrator agent or did you just tell
cloud code to like figure it out? Um, I
used cloud code as an orchestrator
agent. Basically just started, hey, go
through, look at the man pages, look at
all the tools on the SI. I had an entire
list of them. It run the man page. And I
said, if there's no man page, run the
tool, make sure it runs accurately, and
see the command line flags, and then
look it up online to see if there's any
documentation. It literally is using
cloud code. Then I said, red team it,
make sure it works. I actually asked a
question like you just gave it. I'm
like, you know, because I'm learning,
too. I don't know how to solve this
issue. If I did, I want to do a
hackathon. Um, so I'm trying to figure
it out, but again, when I rebuilt it, it
literally is natural language into
Claude, asking the same questions you
just did, and just continually fighting
with it. And I fought with it for about
an hour and a half before I said, "Okay,
are we we're probably good enough? Let's
go ahead and start running it through
analysis." Great question.
>> I had a my question is similar about
context rot. I think and some latest
research just found even with these
million context windows, I mean, the
first turn it gets dumb. I mean it it
you got a larger a larger window, but it
still gets done really quick. And I
found this myself with OpenCloud. I
tried to use a million window. I have to
crank it down to to compact it like a
100 thousand tokens,
>> right?
>> For what you're doing, isn't it is it as
easy as just start a new session to get
rid of the context rot? I mean, that's
what we're doing, right? Anything that
you're doing or did you find a better
way? There's not a better way right now,
but I'm looking at if you wanted to
expand upon this in an enterprise
setting and have it run across multiple
systems at one time doing like let's use
pre-fish analysis looking for P.exe on a
thousand systems that scale is going to
create context rot pretty quickly. Um so
on a single system like standard
forensics, no problem. Just start
restart just like you do on you know
claude will say hey we ran out of
context start a new chat. Here it's a
little bit different because if we
really want something enterpriseworthy,
it's going to have to be able to
maintain its current data set across a
longer period of time. Thread, you know,
threat intelligence, all these other
feeds that you could see where this
thing could go.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I had a question on you
mentioned that it had 100% accuracy on
the the
>> my report. Yeah. Exactly. Uh my question
exactly on that is is that part of your
SANS class? Did you do any assessment on
is cloud code cheating? looking up
answers online comparatively to actually
>> the fair point, but the amount of detail
that's in there, it would be um
shocking. Now, I could probably
disconnect it from, you know, certain
things to be able say do not look up
online, you know, and to be able to do
those checks, but great question. Um I
assume no, but uh based on the amount of
detail that's in there, it would be
shocking that it didn't pull it from
directly toolbased output. The other
thing in there we do have is a log of
every single command that had run and
the output files, every single thing
that it built a report off of. So you do
know that it's actually grabbing it
locally. But is it inferring things
online? Oh, good question.